Register of the Gleb Struve Papers 1810-1985
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1810-1985 (Boxes 69-148)
  - International Symposium On Soviet Literature In the Sixties, Munich, 1963
    - Papers delivered at conference, typescript copies
      - Benno, Peter,"The Politics of Current Soviet Literature" (Folder 8)
      - Friedburg, Maurice, "Soviet Literary Output: 1956-1962" (Folder 9)
      - Gaev, A., "Literatura poslestalinskogo desiatiletiia" (Folder 10)
      - Rubin, Burton, "Liberal Soviet Writers and Their Critics" (Folder 11)
      - Rzhevskii, L., "O Iazyke sovremennoi sovetskoi literatury" (Folder 12)
  - Ivanov, Georgii
    - Correspondence between Georgii Ivanov and Gleb Struve, 1931-1938 (Folder 13)
    - Articles re Ivanov from scholarly journals, 1958-1967 (Folder 14)
  - Ivanov, Viacheslav
    - Writings, "K issledovaniiu poetiki Bloka ('Shagi komandora')", pre-printed copy, n.d. (Folder 15)
    - Scholarly articles
      - Soviet scholarly journals, photocopies, 1968-1974 (Folder 16)
      - Stammler, Heinrich, "Viacheslav Ivanov's Image of Man", typescript, n.d. (Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous poetry, photocopy of typescript notebook (?), n.d. (Folder 18)
    - Struve, Gleb. Miscellaneous handwritten notes, n.d. (Folder 19)
    - Clipping re Viacheslav Ivanov Symposium, Rome, Novoye Russkoye Slovo, July 16, 1983 (Folder 20)
  - Ivask, Iurii
    - Correspondence
      - 1952-1955 (Folder 21)
      - 1956-1958 (Folder 22)
      - 1959-1961 (Folder 23)
      - 1962-1965 (Box 91, Folder 1)
      - 1966-1968 (Folder 2)
      - 1969 (Folder 3)
      - 1970-1971 (Folder 4)
      - 1972 (Folder 5)
      - 1973 (Folder 6)
      - 1974 (Folder 7)
      - 1975 (Folder 8)
      - 1976 (Folder 9)
      - 1977 (Folder 10)
      - 1978 (Folder 11)
      - 1979 (Folder 12)
      - 1980 (Folder 13)
      - 1981 (Folder 14)
      - 1982-1984 (Folder 15)
    - Writings
      - "Acmeism Project", includes report on interviews with participants in Acmeist Movement, typescript copy, 1960-1963 (Box 92, Folder 1)
      - Poetry, typescript copies, 1957-1980 (Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous writing. Includes articles, book reviews and bibliographies, typescript copies and drafts, 1960-1969 (Folder 3)
    - Clippings, 1956-1963 (Folder 4)
  - Jones, William. See John Paradise
  - Johnston, Charles. Translations, typescript, n.d.
    - "The Bronze Horseman" by Aleksandr Pushkin (Folder 5)
    - "The Demon" by Mikhail Lermontov (Folder 6)
  - Kantor, Mikhail. The Mikhail Kantor Archive. Includes correspondence and other material related to the publication of Zveno, Chisla, Vstrechi and Iakor', 1923-1934
    - Zveno, Jan. 3, 1926-June 19, 1927, printed copies (Folder 7-14)
    - Zveno and Vstrechi
      - Correspondence
        - General, 1927-1934 (Box 93, Folder 1-2)
        - Adamovich, Georgii, 1926-1934. Includes typescript copies (Folder 3-4)
        - Aldanov, Mark, 1927 (Folder 5)
        - Astrov, Vladimir, 1927 (Folder 6)
        - Bakhtin, N., 1927 (Folder 7)
        - Berberova, Nina, 1927 (Folder 8)
        - Bitsilli, P., 1927-1933 (Folder 9-10)
        - Blokh, Andrei, 1927 (Folder 11)
        - Blokh, Raisa, 1933-1934 (Folder 12)
        - Bunin, Ivan.
          - June-Nov. 1934 (Folder 13)
          - Jan.-Sept. 1935 (Folder 14)
          - Correspondence with Mark Slonim included in above, 1933 (Folder 15)
          - List of translations of his works included in above, 1934 (Folder 16)
        - Dekhterev, Aleksandr, writings, 1934 (Folder 17)
        - Gippius, Zinaida, 1927 (Folder 18)
        - Ivanov, Georgii, 1925 (Folder 19)
        - Khodasevich, n.d. (Folder 20)
        - Knorring, N., 1926-1928 (Folder 21)
        - Koni, A., 1922-1923 (Folder 22)
        - Kuznetsova, Galina, 1927 (Folder 23)
        - Ladinskii, A., 1927 (Folder 24)
        - Lozinskii, G., 1925-1934 (Folder 25-26)
        - Mochul'skii, Konstantin, 1925-1928 (Folder 27)
        - Ossorgine, M., 1933 (Folder 28)
        - Otsup, Nikolai, 1927-1928 (Folder 29)
        - Remizov, Aleksei, 1925-1936 (Folder 30)
        - Saltykov, A., 1934 (Folder 31)
        - Sazonova, Iu., 1933 (Folder 32)
        - Shletser, V., 1927-1934 (Folder 33-34)
        - Shmelev, Ivan, 1934 (Folder 35)
        - Struve, Gleb, 1928 (Folder 36)
        - Teffi, 1927 (Folder 37)
        - Terapiano, Iurii, 1928 (Folder 38)
        - Vishniak, Mikhail, 1927 (Folder 39)
        - Volkonskii, Prince S., 1926-1934 (Folder 40)
        - Weidle, Vladimir, 1925-1934 (Folder 41-42)
        - Zvonko-Borovskii, 1927-1928 (Folder 43)
        - Business correspondence, Zveno, 1926-1928 (Box 94, Folder 1)
        - Typescript copies of correspondence re Vstrechi (Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous notes, Gleb Struve. See also untitled article by Gleb Struve re Vsterchi (Folder 3)
    - Poslednie Novosti, financial accounts, 1927 (Folder 4)
    - Iakor'
      - Correspondence of Mikhail Kantor
        - Adamovich, Georgii, 1934-1935 (Folder 5)
        - Bitsilli, P., 1935 (Folder 6)
        - Struve, Gleb, 1935 (Folder 7)
      - Reviews in emigre press, 1934-1936 (Folder 8)
      - See also Gleb Struve, "K istorii russkoi zarubezhnoi literatury. Kak sostavlialas' antologiia 'Iakor'"
    - Vstrechi, clippings, 1934-1936 (Folder 9)
    - Writings. Kantor, Mikhail, "Sorevnovanie diletantov", 1928, typescript copy and notes (Folder 10)
    - Obituary, Georgii Adamovich, "Pamiati M. L. Kantor", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, Jan. 14, 1971 (Folder 11)
  - Karlinsky, Simon. Printed matter
    - Articles in scholarly journals, 1983-1984 (Folder 12)
    - Newspapers, 1966-1983 (Folder 13)
  - Kartashev, Anton
    - Correspondence between Anton Kartashev and Gleb Struve, 1930-1956 (Folder 14)
    - Writings,"Idea Natsional'nogo Soiuza", handwritten manuscript, n.d. (Folder 15)
  - Kataev, Valentin. Miscellaneous printed matter, 1936-1969 (Folder 16)
  - Katkov, Georgii
    - Correspondence between Georgii Katkov and Gleb Struve, 1939-1973 (Folder 17)
    - Clippings, 1958-1985 (Folder 18)
  - Kaverin, Ven'iamin. Miscellaneous printed matter, 1936-1973 (Folder 19)
  - Kayden, Eugene
    - Correspondence between Eugene Kayden and Gleb Struve, 1959-1966 (Folder 20)
    - Translations of Russian poetry, galley proofs and reprints, 1971-1975 (Folder 21-22)
  - Kerenskii, Aleksandr
    - Correspondence Between Aleksandr Kerenskii and Gleb Struve, 1940-1956 (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, 1936-1981 (Folder 2)
  - Khlebnikov, Velimir. Miscellaneous printed matter, 1977-1978 (Folder 3)
  - Khodasevich, Vladislav
    - Correspondence between Vladislav Khodasevich and Gleb Struve, 1930-1935 (Folder 4)
    - Writings, "Mednyi vsadnik", typescript article corrected by hand, n.d. (Folder 5)
    - Struve, Gleb. Bibliographies of Khodasevich poetry, typescript, n.d. (Folder 6)
    - Clippings from newspapers and journals
      - Articles re Khodasevich, 1936-1983 (Folder 7)
      - Writings by Khodasevich, 1925-1936 (Folder 8-9)
      - Writings by "Gulliver", 1932-1937 (Folder 10)
  - Khomiakov, Gennadii
    - Correspondence between Gennadii Khomiakov and Gleb Struve
      - 1952-1969 (Folder 11)
      - 1970-1982 (Folder 12)
    - Clippings, 1948-1984 (Folder 13)
  - Khovin, Victor. Printed matter. Includes poems and other writings by Khovin, photocopies, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Khrisagonov, Mikhail
    - Correspondence between Mikhail Khrisagonov and Gleb Stuve, 1970-1980 (Folder 2)
    - Printed matter. Includes clippings and reprints of articles, 1922-1976 (Folder 3)
  - Klenovskii, Dmitrii
    - Correspondence between Dmitrii Klenovskii and Gleb Struve
      - 1952-1957 (Folder 4)
      - 1958-1959 (Folder 5)
      - 1960-1961 (Folder 6)
      - 1962-1964 (Folder 7)
      - 1965-1968 (Folder 8)
      - 1969-1970 (Folder 9)
      - 1971-1972 (Folder 10)
      - 1973-1976 (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - Writings
      - "Predgor'e", typescript copy. Includes poetry from 1918-1958 (Folder 2)
      - "Sel'skie i bozhestvennye igry", translation of A. de Renier, holograph, n.d. (Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous poetry, typescript, n.d. (Folder 4)
    - Clippings, 1956-1982 (Folder 5)
  - Klimov, Evgenii. Clippings, 1952-1985 (Folder 6)
  - Kliuev, Nikolai
    - Correspondence between Ettore Lo Gatto and Gleb Struve, 1947-1968 (Folder 7)
    - Biographical material. Lo Gatto, Ettore, reminiscences re Kliuev. Includes typescript copy in Italian and typescript and printed copy of Russian translation, 1953 (Folder 8)
    - Writings
      - "Pogorel'shchina"
        - Typescript copy given by author to Lo Gatto, 1931 (Folder 9)
        - Draft of translation by John Glad, typescript, n.d. (Folder 10)
      - "Serdtse edinoroga", title page with handwritten dedication to Lo Gatto, photocopy, 1929 (Folder 11)
      - "Zaozerie", same as above (Folder 12)
  - Knorring, Irina. Clipping, miscellaneous poetry, n.d. (Folder 13)
  - Kochetov, Vsevolod. Clippings, 1958-1970 (Folder 14)
  - Kondratiev, Aleksandr
    - Correspondence of Aleksandr Kondratiev
      - General, 1960 (Folder 15)
      - Aseev, Aleksandr, 1953-1954 (Folder 16)
      - Rudneva, Ekaterina, 1955-1957 (Folder 17)
      - Struve, Gleb, 1925-1936 (Folder 18)
    - Correspondence of Gleb Struve
      - General, 1926-1970 (Folder 19)
      - Andreeva, Elena, 1969-1971 (Folder 20)
      - Aseev, Aleksandr, 1969 (Folder 21)
    - Writings
      - Poems, short story, and reminiscences, manuscript, n.d. (Folder 22)
      - Miscellaneous material, typescript and photocopies, n.d. (Folder 23)
  - Konstantinov, Fr. Dimitrii. Clippings, 1963-1985 (Folder 24)
  - Kontinent. Miscellaneous material, includes clippings of reviews and publisher's introduction, 1975-1984 (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - Koriakov, Mikhail
    - Correspondence betwee Mikhail Koriakov and Gleb Struve, 1953-1975 (Folder 2)
    - Clippings, 1950-1976 (Folder 3-7)
    - Clippings, 1950-1976 (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Korzhavin, Naum. Clippings, 1974-1985 (Folder 2)
  - Kozlovskii, Prince Petr
    - Printed matter
      - Dorrow, Wilhelm, Furst Kosloffsky, Druck und Verlag von Philip Reclam jun., Leipzig, 1846, photocopy (Folder 3)
      - Clippings, photocopies and typescript copies of excerpts from books and articles, 1917-1963 (Folder 4)
    - Biographical material
      - Typescript excerpts from secondary sources (Folder 5)
      - Kozlovskii in the correspondence and memoirs of contemporaries, typescript excerpts, 1803-1927 (Folder 6-8)
    - Correspondence of Prince Petr Kozlovskii. Holograph (photocopy), 1810. Original in Restricted Series
      - Rumiantsev, Count, 1810 (Folder 9)
      - Varshavskii, Kniaz'(?), 1839 (Folder 10)
    - Correspondence related to Prince Petr Kozlovskii
      - General
        - Typescript copies, 1810-1817 (Folder 11)
        - Photocopies, 1818-1821 (Folder 12)
      - Archivio di Stato, Torino, handwritten copies, 1814-1817 (Folder 13)
      - Archives Etrangeres, Affaires de Sardaigne
        - 1815-1818, typescript copies (Folder 14)
        - 1816-1819, handwritten copies (Folder 15)
    - Correspondence related to Prince Petr Kozlovskii
      - Barante a Thiers, handwritten copies of printed correspondence, 1836-1837 (Box 100, Folder 1)
      - Berry Papers, 1789-1803, handwritten copies (Folder 2)
      - Custine and Varnhagen, printed copy, 1840-1848 (Folder 3)
      - Liverpool Papers, 1799-1803, handwritten copies (Folder 4)
      - Naval Papers and Letters of Admiral Mitchell, 1799-1803, handwritten copies (Folder 5)
      - Nelson Papers, same as above
      - Public Record Office, Chancery Lane, 1807-1810, typescript copies. Includes correspondence of Hill, Canning and Kozlovskii (Folder 6)
    - Correspondence of Gleb Struve
      - General. Includes correspondence with libraries and archives re research material used, 1950-1957 (Folder 7)
      - Kennan, George, 1969-1971 (Folder 8)
    - General
      - "Kozlovskii o Nikolae I", typescript excerpt from Russkaia Starina, June 1896 (Folder 9)
      - Posner, S., "Les Lettres du Prince Pierre Koslovsky a Chateaubriand et a Madame de Stael", typescript article, n.d. (Folder 10)
      - Struve, Gleb, notes, n.d. (Folder 11)
      - Miscellaneous typescript material
        - Iakovlev, Senator Lev (Folder 12)
        - Lieven, Princess Sophie (Folder 13)
  - Krachkovskii, Dmitrii. See Klenovskii, Dmitrii
  - Kremnev, Ivan
    - Writings. "Puteshestvie moego brata Alekseiia v stranu krest'ianskoi utopii", clipping, 1976 (Folder 14)
    - Smith, R., "Introduction", typescript, n.d. (Folder 15)
    - Struve, Gleb, miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Folder 16)
    - Clippings, 1955-1982 (Folder 17)
  - Kriger, Mary. Writings, holograph and printed copies, 1948 (Folder 18-19)
  - Krymov, Vladimir. Clippings, 1949-1982 (Folder 20)
  - Kuchelbecker, Wilhelm. Struve, Gleb, miscellaneous typescript and handwritten notes, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - Kuprin, Aleksandr. Clippings, 1947-1983 (Folder 2)
  - Kuskova, Ekaterina
    - Correspondence between Ekaterina Kuskova and Gleb Struve, 1938-1958 (Folder 3)
    - Clippings, 1930-1957 (Folder 4-6)
  - Kutepov, Aleksandr. Clippings, 1928-1981 (Folder 7)
  - Kuz'min, Mikhail. Printed matter, 1975-1979 (Folder 8)
  - Kuznetsov, Anatolii
    - Correspondence between Anatolii Kuznetsov and Gleb Struve, 1967-1979 (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, 1969-1972 (Folder 2)
  - Larionov, Mikhail
    - Correspondence of Gleb Struve
      - General, 1968 (Folder 3)
      - Larionova, A., 1968-1971 (Folder 4)
      - Larionov, Mikhail, 1952-1953. Includes originals and typescript copies (Folder 5)
      - "Les Amis de Gontcharova and Larionov" (Folder 6)
        - 1962-1966
    - Writings. "Pochemu my raskrashevaemsia. Manifest Futuristov", photocopy of printed original, n.d. (Folder 7)
    - Clippings, 1979 (Folder 8)
  - Lebedev, Viacheslav
    - Correspondence between Gleb Struve and Viacheslav Lebedev, 1959-1967 (Folder 9)
    - Writings, typescript drafts of poetry, 1929-1967. See also Aleksei Eisner, "O poterianykh poetakh" (Folder 10)
  - Leonov, Leonid
    - Struve, Gleb, miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Folder 11)
    - Gorbachev, G., "O 'Vore' Leonida Leonova", photocopy of printed material, n.d. (Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous clippings and reprints, 1964-1983 (Folder 13)
  - Lermontov, Mikhail. Printed matter. Reprints of scholarly articles, 1956-1964 (Folder 14)
  - Leskov, Nikolai. Printed matter. Reprints of scholarly articles, 1954-1982 (Folder 15)
  - Levitskii, Sergei. Clippings, 1956-1983 (Folder 16)
  - Limonov, Eduard. Clippings, 1975-1984 (Folder 17)
  - Litvinskii, V. Clippings, 1948-1964 (Folder 18)
  - L'vov, Andrei. Clippings, 1982-1985 (Folder 19)
  - Lukacz, Georges. Clippings, 1950-1976 (Folder 20)
  - Lukash, Ivan
    - Correspondence between Ivan Lukash and Gleb Struve, 1924-1934 (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - Writings, "Sozhzhennyi serafim", typescript draft, 1935 (Folder 2)
    - Clippings, 1930's-1981 (Folder 3)
  - Maiakovskii, Vladimir. Clippings, 1939-1984 (Folder 4)
  - Makovskii, Sergei. Clippings, 1948-1974 (Folder 5)
  - Maksimov, Vladimir. Clippings, 1963-1985 (Folder 6)
  - Mandel'shtam, Nadezhda
    - Correspondence of Nadezhda Mandel'stam
      - Ivask, Iurii, 1976, photocopy (Folder 7)
      - Shakhovskoi, Bishop Ioann, 1979, photocopy (Folder 8)
      - Struve, Gleb, 1966 (Folder 9)
    - Correspondence about Nadezhda Mandel'shtam. Letter by unknown author, typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 10)
    - Biographical material. Reck, Vera, "Nadezhda Yakovlevna Mandel'shtam", article describing the death and funeral of Nadezhda Mandel'shtam, typescript, n.d. (Folder 11)
    - Writings
      - "Zhylploshchad' v nadstroike". Printed copy with handwritten translation by Gleb Struve, n.d. (Folder 12)
      - Typescript excerpts from her memoirs, n.d. (Folder 13)
    - Critical material
      - A. K., annotations to Vospominaniia, typescript, n.d. (Folder 14)
      - Filippov, Boris, review of Vospominaniia, typescript, n.d. (Folder 15)
    - Clippings, 1970-1983 (Folder 16)
  - Mandel'shtam, Osip
    - Correspondence of Osip Mandel'shtam. "Pis'ma k V. I. Ivanovu". Typescript draft for Struve, Gleb, Polnoe sobranie sochinenii, n.d. (Folder 17)
    - Bibliography. Miscellaneous material, photocopies and typescripts, n.d. (Folder 18)
    - Biographical material
      - Anonymous, translation into English of reminiscences re Osip Mandel'shtam, holograph, n.d. (Folder 19)
      - Miscellaneous typescript material, n.d. Includes reminiscences re Mandel'shstam (Folder 20)
    - Writings
      - Poetry
        - Photocopies, R. Thomson and Harvard University material, 1930-1937 (Folder 21-22)
        - Miscellaneous typescripts, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 1)
        - Clippings and photocopies of published work, 1924-1980 (Folder 2)
      - Prose
        - Typescript copies, n.d.
          - "Batum" (Folder 3)
          - "Chetvertaia proza" (Folder 4)
          - "Pushkin i Skriabin" (Folder 5)
          - "Razgovor o Dante" (Folder 6)
        - Photocopy, Shary, illustrated by N. Lapshin, printed copy, n.d. (Folder 7)
        - Handwritten copies, n.d.
          - "Gosudarstvo i ritm" (Folder 8)
          - "Iakhontov" (Folder 9)
          - "Poet o sebe", Chitatel' i pisatel', No. 46, 1928 (Folder 10)
    - Critical material
      - Ivask, Iurii
        - "O Mandel'shtame", typescript, n.d. (Folder 11)
        - "Some Aspects of Mandel'shtam's Poetry", typescript, n.d. (Folder 12)
      - Freidin, Gregory, "Osip Mandel'shtam: The Poetry Of Time", 1976, typescript, n.d. (Folder 13)
      - Ronen, Omri, "Leksicheskii povtor, podtekst, i smysl v poete Osipe Mandel'shtame", typescript, n.d. (Folder 14)
      - Miscellaneous typescript material, n.d. (Folder 15)
      - Printed matter
        - Scholarly journals, 1964-1982 (Folder 16-18)
        - Scholarly journals, 1964-1982 (Box 105, Folder 1)
        - Newspapers, 1913-1984 (Folder 2)
      - Translation. Miscellaneous typescript and printed translations of Mandel'shtam's work, n.d. (Folder 3)
  - Margolin, Iurii. Clippings, 1950-1976 (Folder 4)
  - Markov, Vladimir
    - Correspondence betwen Vladimir Markov and Gleb Struve
      - 1949-1952 (Folder 5)
      - 1953-1954 (Folder 6)
      - 1955-1956 (Folder 7)
      - 1957 (Folder 8)
      - 1958 (Folder 9)
      - 1959 (Box 106, Folder 1)
      - 1960-1961 (Folder 2)
      - 1962-1963 (Folder 3)
      - 1964-1968 (Folder 4)
      - 1969-1972 (Folder 5)
      - 1973-1978 (Folder 6)
      - 1979-1985 (Folder 7)
    - Writings. Miscellaneous articles, typescript and printed copies, 1978 (Folder 8)
  - Maslov, Georgii
    - Biographical material. Miscellaneous printed matter, n.d. (Folder 9)
    - Critical material. Gumilev, Nikolai, "Arion", typescript article, n.d. (Folder 10)
    - Writings, poetry
      - Handwritten copies of poems received from Iulian Oksman, n.d. (Folder 11)
      - Miscellaneous typescripts, photocopies and clippings, 1922-1934 (Box 107, Folder 1)
      - "Put' vo mrake, doroga Omsk-Krasnoiarsk, ianvar'-fevral', 1920". Includes Civil War poetry compiled from Nikolai Iakovlev's archive, 1920, typescript (Folder 2)
  - Matskevich, Josef (Folder 3)
    - Correspondence between Josef Matskevich and Gleb Struve, 1957-1975
    - Clippings and miscellaneous material, 1963-1985
  - Medvedev, Roy
    - Writings. Qui a ecrit "Le Don Paisible", Christian Bourgeois ed., Paris, 1975, photocopy (Folder 4)
    - Clippings, 1983-1985 (Folder 5)
  - Meier, Iurii. Clippings, 1981-1985 (Folder 6-7)
  - Merezhkovskii, Dmitrii. Clippings, 1934-1979 (Folder 8)
  - Merimee, Prosper
    - Correspondence between Gleb Struve and M. Parturier, 1931 (Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous material. Includes Gleb Struve's notes, n.d. (Folder 10)
    - Clippings, 1929-1936 (Folder 11)
  - Milosz, Czeslaw. Clippings, 1968-1984 (Folder 12)
  - Miranda, Francisco de
    - Correspondence of Gleb Struve re Miranda archival material, 1946 (Box 108, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence from Miranda's archive, 1790-1815, typescript copies (Folder 2)
    - Correspondence re Miranda, 1787-1815, typescript copies (Folder 3)
    - Correspondence between Samuel Bentham and Admiral Mordvinoff, 1830-1884 Includes Mordvinoff's project for a Russian Constitution, typescript copy (Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous material. Includes clippings and notes, 1950 (Folder 5)
  - Mochalova, Ol'ga, "Literaturnye Vstrechi", typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 6)
  - Morkovin, Vadim
    - Correspondence between Vadim Morkovin and Gleb Struve, 1960-1971 (Folder 7)
    - Writings
      - Untitled reminiscences, manuscript, n.d. (Folder 8)
      - "Obshchestvo dostoevskogo v Prage", Ceskoslovenskaia Rusistika XVI, offprint, 1971 (Folder 9)
  - Morshen, Nikolai
    - Correspondence between Nikolai Morshen and Gleb Struve, 1957-1985 (Folder 10)
    - Writings, typescript drafts of poetry, n.d. (Folder 11)
  - Mozhaiskaia, O. Writings, poetry, typescript, n.d. (Folder 12)
  - Nabokov, Vladimir
    - Correspondence of Gleb Struve
      - General, 1936-1939 (Folder 13)
      - Auslander, Andrei, 1974-1975 (Folder 14)
      - British publishers re publication of Nabokov's early work, 1930-1937 (Folder 15)
      - Nabokov, Vera, 1949-1985 (Folder 16)
      - Nabokov, Vladimir, typescript copies
        - 1925-1935 (Folder 17)
        - 1936-1975 (Jan., May 1948 and April 1975, original) (Folder 18)
    - Writings, handwritten poem, 1923 (Folder 19)
    - General
      - "Bratiia Kruglogo Stola", protocol of meeting. Includes pencil caricatures of members, 1923 (Folder 20)
      - Bibliographies, typescript and handwritten, n.d. (Folder 21)
      - Miscellaneous typescript and handwritten material. Includes poetry, 1974-1981 (Box 109, Folder 1)
      - Struve, Gleb, handwriten notes, n.d. (Folder 2)
      - Untitled manuscript for book re Nabokov, typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 3-4)
    - Printed matter
      - Articles from scholarly journals, 1936-1983 (Folder 5)
      - Clippings from newspapers, 1923-1984 (Folder 6)
  - Narokov, Nikolai (Marchenko). Clippings, 1952-1969 (Folder 7)
  - Nartsyssov, Boris. Clippings, 1954-1980 (Folder 8)
  - Nedobrovo, Nikolai
    - Correspondence of Nikolai Nedobrovo
      - Anrep, Boris, 1910-1914. Photocopies. Originals in Restricted Series (Folder 9)
      - Pestovskii, V. A., typescript copies of published material, 1913-1915 (Folder 10)
      - Znamenskaia, Vera, 1913-1918
        - Photocopies (Folder 11)
        - Typescript copies (Folder 12)
      - Excerpts from miscellaneous correspondence collected by V. Znamenskaia, 1967 (Folder 13)
    - Correspondence between Iu. Sazonova and Gleb Struve, 1952 (Folder 14)
    - Biographical material. Clippings and photocopies of published material, 1923-1954 (Folder 15)
    - Writings
      - Poetry
        - Iudif'. Tragediia v stikhakh, printed copy with holograph annotations, 1922 (?) (Folder 16)
        - Leatherbound book of poetry, 1904. Holograph (photocopy). Original in Restricted Series (Box 110, Folder 1)
        - N. V. Nedobrovo. Stikhotvoreniia, tearsheet, n.d. (Folder 2)
        - Photocopies of published material, 1904-1914 (Folder 3)
        - Typescript copies, n.d. (Folder 4)
      - Prose. Photocopies
        - Published material, 1910-1914 (Folder 5)
        - Typescript excerpt of critical article re Akhmatova with holograph note from Akhmatova to Znamenskaia, 1964 (Folder 6)
    - Critical material. Struve, Gleb
      - Bibliography, typescript, n.d. (Folder 7)
      - Commentaries on correspondence of Nikolai Nedobrovo, typescript, n.d. (Folder 8)
      - Excerpt from Anna Akhmatova, pp. 63-126, photocopy of proof copy (Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Folder 10)
  - Nekrasov, Viktor. Clippings, 1962-1985 (Folder 11-12)
  - Nicolaevsky, Boris
    - Correspondence between Boris Nicolaevsky and Gleb Struve, 1937-1965 (Folder 13)
    - Clippings, 1947-1982 (Folder 14)